<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reflections on Phil in the Blank</title>
    <link>/categories/reflections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reflections on Phil in the Blank</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020- Phil Nguyen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/reflections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Ode to Young Adulthood</title>
      <link>/posts/ode-adulthood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ode-adulthood/</guid>
      <description>There’s this drawing of a banana. Toward the stem it is fresh, premature, and budding with potential; toward the other end it is weathered and well-defined, filled with the hard-earned sweetness and history that a full life bestows.
Two dashed lines split the picture into thirds, and middle age is the centerpiece. Before it, the world pulls you in with its long and wide arms, with its promises of invention and discovery, grievance and uncertainty, joy and adventure; afterward, the world opens itself up again, only to allow you to return that which you have reaped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2019</title>
      <link>/posts/fall-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/fall-2019/</guid>
      <description>I’m finally finished with the semester. Soon I’ll be heading home to see my parents, camp in Joshua Tree National Park, and soak in the California sunshine. The break is much needed, as is some perspective.
A lazy list of notable things:
 I applied to the Masters in Complex Systems and Data Science program at UVM. This was a long process, mostly because I desire the kind of work that involves making connections with others, deep conversation, and facilitating personal transformation, but also because I was riddled with fear and self-doubt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>