<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>musings on Phil in the Blank</title>
    <link>/categories/musings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in musings on Phil in the Blank</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020- Phil Nguyen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Devotion</title>
      <link>/posts/devotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/devotion/</guid>
      <description>It’s the day I’m supposed to be camping in Joshua Tree, but I find myself driving up the coast instead, hunting for answers. Something is calling me north to Santa Barbara. It feels familiar, like a warm embrace from a distant friend, an aged habit that continues to linger, yet it remains entirely nameless. A ghost is whispering.
I arrive, park in front of my old apartment complex, and shuffle up the steps to the second floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bearing Witness</title>
      <link>/posts/witness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/witness/</guid>
      <description>There were 16 of us nestled in the sunlit alcove of the church. I looked at the stranger sitting on a navy-blue cushion before me and wondered what she was thinking about. She smiled at me, and I smiled back. We introduced ourselves and made small talk, as did everyone else and their adjacent stranger. Then the bell chimed, and the room fell into silence.
We turned our gaze to Mike, the PI of the study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shoreless Seeds and Stardust</title>
      <link>/posts/seeds-stardust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/seeds-stardust/</guid>
      <description>I ventured out onto the lake today, this time beyond the frozen crest that marks the boundary between bay and lake, contemplating the last line of Maria Popova’s Figuring: “What will survive of us are shoreless seeds and stardust.” My saunter figured into a sprint as the mountains came into view, and soon the voices behind me were no more than whispers. Minutes later I ran into a couple playing in the snow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons in Adulthood</title>
      <link>/posts/adulthood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/adulthood/</guid>
      <description>Crossroads My year of service with City Year, New Hampshire was coming to an end. I knew that I didn’t want to become a teacher anymore, but I still liked the idea of shaping the young minds of the future, so I applied to Boston University’s Masters program in Educational Leadership and Policy Studies.
I was waiting for my flight home in O’Hare International Airport when I received the news. The man sitting next to me happened to notice – he must have glimpsed the email’s subject line – and congratulated me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serendipity</title>
      <link>/posts/serendipity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/serendipity/</guid>
      <description>We sift through life without any compasses to guide us through the messy unknown, like aimless treasure hunters searching for diamonds in the dark.
The unknown scares us. We&amp;rsquo;re not so comfortable immersed in this infinite expanse. Maybe this is why the human brain has evolved the ability to construe stories from unrelated anecdotes and scattered tidbits: we find comfort in connecting the dots, we tell ourselves everything happens for a reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter</title>
      <link>/posts/winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/winter/</guid>
      <description>Arbiter of cessation, master of endings, a gust inevitably endured. Clench your jaw now, the exchange is complete: Snow and frost for people and sidewalks. Inches and burdens for sauntered footfalls.
There is a season between seasons a bridge that is crossed by the plentiful few. Adults and scientists seek it endlessly though only the children know of its whereabouts. But don’t bother with asking–– they’re sworn to the promises of secrecy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgiveness</title>
      <link>/posts/forgiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/forgiveness/</guid>
      <description>Forgiveness moves us toward a better future by inviting us to look at the past, at the unrelenting, painful ghosts that continue to permeate and darken each of our lives.
Sometimes we need to feel rage, to tussle with guilt, to fall into our sorrows before we can forgive. No, forgiveness is not about avoiding these emotions. Rather, forgiveness asks us to show up daily with unwavering courage, compassion, receptivity, and kindness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feelings</title>
      <link>/posts/feelings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/feelings/</guid>
      <description>Feelings are fleeting by nature, like the passage of clouds on a warm summer day.
Though too often we wear them like immutable masks and declare, &amp;ldquo;This is me. This is all I will ever be.&amp;rdquo; Sad. Resentful. Despondent. Happy. In truth they are masks, transient facades that hide a more true and vulnerable sense of self.
We put these masks on when we&amp;rsquo;re scared, when we&amp;rsquo;re too afraid to ask for attention and love; when we&amp;rsquo;re on the verge of breaking, but don&amp;rsquo;t know how to ask for help.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>