<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ABCD on Phil in the Blank</title>
    <link>/tags/abcd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ABCD on Phil in the Blank</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020- Phil Nguyen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/abcd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ABCD Brain Analysis Tool</title>
      <link>/projects/abcd-bat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/abcd-bat/</guid>
      <description>This is the abstract I submitted to OHBM 2020 for the ABCD Brain Analysis Tool. The GUI was built under the guidance of the great Bader Chaarani. We thought about naming it something punny after Bader - i.e. The ABCD BAD Tool - but we couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of anything appropriate for submission.
Anyways, here&amp;rsquo;s the abstract:
 Introduction:
  Given the computational and analytical expertise required to study large MRI datasets such as that generated by the Adolescent Brain Cognitive Development (ABCD) study, we created the ABCD Brain Analysis Tool (BAT) to allow researchers from various academic backgrounds to utilize fMRI data in their research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABCD Prematurity Analysis</title>
      <link>/projects/prematurity-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/prematurity-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Examining the relationship between prematurity, mental health, and neurocognition in ABCD. Ran some T-tests and created visualizations.
This is an interactive HTML page using R Markdown for an analysis I did for my PI. Source code here; GIF demonstrating below.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to R and Tidyverse workshop</title>
      <link>/projects/intro-r-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/intro-r-workshop/</guid>
      <description>  Slides for an introductory R and Tidyverse workshop I lead for undergraduates and graduate students working in our lab. We ran 4 workshops total:
  Workshop 1
  Workshop 2
  Workshop 3
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences in Cognition and BOLD Signal Related to Early Stages of Puberty</title>
      <link>/projects/ncog-pub-rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/ncog-pub-rome/</guid>
      <description>Poster I presented at OHBM 2019 in Rome - &amp;ldquo;Differences in Cognition and BOLD Signal Related to Early Stages of Puberty&amp;rdquo;
Tools used for plots and analysis: R and Freesurfer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABCD Data Dictionary</title>
      <link>/projects/abcd-dd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/abcd-dd/</guid>
      <description>A searchable data dictionary and ABCD release notes all in one place. Much easier to navigate compared to NDA&amp;rsquo;s data dictionary.
Unfortunately I can&amp;rsquo;t show the app&amp;rsquo;s source code due to confidentiality, but this is a GIF demonstrating what it does.
  Built using R and Shiny. Data pulled from NDA website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABCD Database Builder</title>
      <link>/projects/abcd-db-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/abcd-db-builder/</guid>
      <description>ABCD Data Downloader: an app I built in Shiny to help ABCD Researchers download ABCD data sets (Unfortunately I can&amp;rsquo;t show the app due to confidentiality, but the source code is here.)
Here is a GIF demonstrating some of the app&amp;rsquo;s functionality.
You can select which spreadsheet(s) you want to download, specific variables from the spreadsheets, which visits to include, and what to name your file.
  Developed with R and Shiny.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>